Account Books
Coventry Historical Society
Coventry Historical Society
- Inventory
  - Town of Coventry Tax Collections - Richard Hale Rose b.1812- d.1872, Selectman, a Prominent Businessman who held many local Town Offices., 1868 (Volume 22)
  - Edward Guy Huntington b.1792- d.1857 - General Store, in the 1850's he is dealing in the production of Hat Bodies, 1857 Account of Estate of William Sprague, 1829-1857 (Volume 23)
  - Coventry Grand List perhaps for State Tax Account 1812- 1st and 2nd Society's, plus Andover Society, 1812-1813 (Volume 28)
  - Isaac Harris – blacksmith (typed transcription). Birthdate unknown died before 1830, 1798-1811 (Volume 122)
  - Day Book for Capt. Packer’s Dry Goods Store on Main St. South Coventry Village - store was open from 1865- 1874., 1867-1868 (Volume 133)
  - Day Book for Capt. Packer's Dry Goods Store on Main St. South Coventry Village, 2nd Volume, 1868 (Volume 135)
  - Richard Dimock Rose b.1842- d.1898 Ledger -Sale of Twist, Silk and other cloth, sometimes in exchange for Rags., 1868-1871 (Volume 182)
  - Royal Manning b. 1776- d.1847 Ledger, a Tavern and General Store owner. The back of the book used by his widow Sally for household accounts, includes receipt for her husband's grave stone., undated (Volume 184)
  - Royal Manning b.1776- d.1847 Tavern and General Store Day Book- The sale of Rum by the gallon is a large part of their business., 1833-1836 (Volume 185)
  - Royal Manning b.1776- d.1847 Tavern and General Store Day Book - This business previously belonged to the Rose family, and so is the subject of several other Acct. Books in this list., 1818-1819 (Volume 186)
  - Henry A. Post b. 1813- d.1853 – Dentist and Hat Maker, Includes expenses building Hat Shop, Stock,Implements- also Estate Inv. Of Richard H. Rose & Mary S. Rose, 1844-1854 (Volume 187)
  - Andrew Kingsbury b.1849- d.1911 - Farm household accounts, names his wife and Children and their expenses as well- "Autumn View Dairy Farm" 1885-1898-Bread & Milk St. North Coventry (Volume 188)
  - Account of Butter Churned and Sold, possibly Kingsbury Dairy- Half of this small book devoted to what looks like Sunday School Attendance Record (2nd Church?), 1884-1890 (Volume 191)
  - Personal Account Book -unsigned, kept by a school teacher in South Coventry who also worked in local mills and did odd jobs. He records his expenses in detail. Original poem "The Country Pedagogue's Arte" included., 1836-1840 (Volume 192)
  - John Rose b.1791-d.1826- Account Book - Tavern and Store, 1819-1826 (Volume 208)
  - Nathan Hale Rose b.1776 -d.1838- Prominent Businessman- Store accounts, then Richard Hale Rose settles Store Accounts for the estate of N.H. Rose 1838, 1825-1838 (Volume 209)
  - William A. Dorman b.1810- d.1888 - Account Book - sale of Livestock, Meat and Farm Produce, Cider, Wood, Soap, use of Wagon, then Town of Coventry Selectman's Accounts, 1826-1868 (Volume 211)
  - Richard Hale Rose -b.1812- d.1878- Accounts of his employees, 1st Church, Estate of Sally Manning, Town of Cov. In C. & M. Woodworth Case, inventory of R.H. Rose Deceased included., 1842-1878 (Volume 212)
  - Pocket sized "Store Book" kept by R.H. Rose with Levi P. Rose- accounts with employees Chauncey Edwards and John Jones, 1843-1845 (Volume 213)
  - Sale of the goods in the Store of David M. Buell b.1797- d.1887 -to settle his estate conducted by W.B. Loomis a neighboring store owner., 1856 (Volume 213.001)
  - Andrew Kingsbury b.1849-d.1911 - An agricultural Journal of plantings, crops, weather from "Autumn View Dairy Farm" Bread & Milk St. Coventry- includes list of town voters., 1902-1909 (Volume 237)
  - Daily Account Book and Journal of George G. Jacobson 18 -1959 Lumber & Hauling Business based in Eagleville, Mansfield, Conn., 1911-1913 (Volume 251)
  - Laying Hens- Jon Harrison's Chicken Account, eggs layed and expences., 1973-1974 (Volume 412)
  - Stanford & Ensign Ledger- Store Keepers (West Hartford) 1844-66, 1880 acct. with Ann Rutherford Medical Attendant, 1844-1880 (Volume 561)
  - Andrew Kingsbury b.1849- d.1911 - Dairy Farm Ledger- Bread & Milk St, North Coventry., 1908 (Volume 594)
  - John B. French b.1821- d.1884 - Blacksmith next to the Pomeroy Stage House on the Boston Tnpk. North Coventry -repaired Stage Coach and did business with every one in town and many passing through., 1842-1846 (Volume 603)
  - John B. French - b.1821- d.1884 -Blacksmith North Coventry - includes Hattie L. Owen Acct. with J.B French Gaurdian 1868-1870, and Hearse Acct. note 1865-67, and 1847 court document., 1845-1855 (Volume 604)
  - John B. French -b.1821- d.1884 -Blacksmith North Coventry (see also #1619), 1858-1866 (Volume 605)
  - William Blythe - Blacksmith West Ashford, CT also work done in Willimantic, Mansfield, Turnerville & lived Columbia, E. Berlin, Wethersfield & Windsor, 1881-1905 (Volume 606)
  - Silas E. Rindge b.1836- d.1880 - Invoice Book 1859-1861 for Store in Chaplin. Then accounts of work done for N.C.White Estate, Receipts for H.D.Woodworth to 1920-probably kept by George G Jacobson, 1859-1920 (Volume 670)
  - Harlan D. Woodworth b.1874-d.1919 - Teamster & Construction work, South Coventry Grain Elevator - draying charges, misc. accounts, receipts, 1914 (Volume 671)
  - Henry F. Dimock b.1842- d.1911 NY Lawyer, Businessman NYC Commisioner of Docks-Personal accounts of Income and expences for his summer home in Coventry where he grew up, gives $40,000 to build Booth & Dimock Library., 1887-1899 (Volume 707)
  - Dr. Timothy Dimock b1800- d.1874-Day Book, Coventry Physician for 45 years account of visits and Charges first years of his practice in Granby, Mass. and Coventry, CT, 1824-1831 (Volume 712)
  - Nathanial Root Jr. b.1806- d. 1879 Account of a variety of work done for Coventry Glass Factory- he was a founding partner. Also work done for many other people, often Hauling, 1845-1869 (Volume 764)
  - Account Book kept by Nathaniel Root Jr.b.1806- d.1864 -for a Wicking, Batting and Yarn Mill owned by N Root Jr, Gad Page and Kingsbury Root., 1835-1839 (Volume 765)
  - Hezekiah Edgerton b.1769- d.1843- This book records work done for John Boynton & many others- Cloth Dressing, wood cutting, carpentry Then a record of labor for several companies, notes on building mill machinery., 1820-1832 (Volume 788)
  - Boyington/Boynton General Store ledger- later Journal of John Boynton R.R. Engineer b.1849-, Watertown Jefferson City, NY, -later used Boynton Genealogy by Mrs. Alice Hoskins b. 1900 m. 1924 of East Windsor Hill, CT, 1844-1849 (Volume 831)
  - Henry S. Goodwin b. 1828- d.1888 worked with his wagon and oxen hauling ashes for Gilbert Turner & Co. bricks, timber, Boynton Wool Carding Machines and other payloads. for local businesses, 1844-1958 (Volume 906)
  - Coventry State Tax Rate Bill 1830- small Account Book not signed- includes Tax List of 1829 and tax for property owners in N. Coventry, S. Coventry and Andover. (Volume 915)
  - Post Office Accounts, unsigned-East Killingly, CT- account of Newspaper and magazine subscriptions, 1869-1870 (Volume 938)
  - Cartridge Maker - Henry W. Mason b. 1833- d.1914 - Five small books, primarily a record of sales with some calculations of costs, and other notes., 1871-1883 (Volume 1004)
  - Four Accounting Class work books marked Day Book, Journal and Ledger- signed by Charles Irving Loomis b. 1886- d.1967, Park Ave. Institute, Bridgeport, CT, 1902 (Volume 1023)
  - Meservey's Book Keeping five student work books- general store and blacksmith accounts, dated 1875- part of the White and Jacobson family collection. (Volume 1053)
  - General Store Day Book of W.L. Wellwood b.1863-d.1932 -Main St. Coventry, 1909 (Volume 1086)
  - Day Book of Jasper Gilbert and/or R. Chapman. General Store Acct. location unknown R. Chapman is the name on the 1st page but J. Gilbert is clearly the writer of the last section and including probate documents Otis Sweet and a receipt for Tavern charges from E. Pomeroy. Gilbert's work for Gilbert Turner & Co. Recorded., 1833-1855 (Volume 1396)
  - Grist Mill and Saw mill Account Book of Elijah Wright b.1730 -d.1802. Elijah Wright Jr. b.1759- d.1839 continued these accounts through 1806 and began recording Coventry Deaths in 1807- His son Harvey continued to record deaths until 1847., 1773-1806 (Volume 1397)
  - John B. French b.1821- d.188 4- Blacksmith North Coventry- Includes Hearse Account 1866-1867, miles driven and names of the deceased. (see 3 other volumes above #603-605), 1866-1873 (Volume 1619)
  - Josephus Dresser b. 1800- d.1867 -Account of Day Labor done for several people including Gilbert Turner & Co. Coventry Glass Works., 1835 (Volume 1620)
  - Account Book of Carl G. Johnson b.1876- d.1956- Record of work done for T. E. Porter,eggs and milk sold from farm, work done for Tolland Leather Board Co., 1897-1926 (Volume 1706)
  - Egg Book- Account of Eggs layed and sold, birds sold, birds on hand, includes names of customers. Margaret E. Jacobson b.1907- d.2005 signs, but may be her mother Mary (White) Jacobson's book., 1913-1916 (Volume 1978)
  - Nathan C. White b.1832- d.1903 - Account Book, includes Town of Coventry First Selectman's Acct.1857-9, 1872-4, Several Probate Accounts, Account of N.C. White with Clark property rentals 1877-80, Stanley & White Grist Mill Acctb1887-, 1857-1889 (Volume 1980)
  - Town of Coventry Account of Building- Building Inspector was Bernard Dion b.1929- d.2017- George G. Jacobson II was on Zoning Board of Appeals (White/Jacobson Collection), 1964-1965 (Volume 2022)
  - Ledger G No.077NLF - E.A. Tracy, Inc. - Shoddy Mill- Eugene A. Tracy, owner b.1850- d.1939, 1917-1925 (Volume 2049)
  - E.A. Tracy, Inc.- Cash Book N0. 185951 - Shoddy Mill- Eugene A. Tracy owner b.1850- d.1939, 1913-1927 (Volume 2050)
  - Journal M No. 027J3 E.A. Tracy, Inc. Shoddy Mill -Eugene A. Tracy owner b. 1850- d. 1939Includes Note on investors dated 1906, 1922-1926 (Volume 2051)
  - Tavern and Store - "Minit Book" kept by John White b.1766 d.1789 at sea- sold Rum by the Gallon, and Quart as well as sugar. He was a sailor and may have imported some items to sell., 1788 (Volume 2221)
  - Small Store and Shoemaking Account Book kept by Frederick White b.1816- d.1847- includes some accounts concerning his Estate., 1841-1946 (Volume 2,221)
  - Small Account Book kept by Henry K. White b.1825- d.1861 may be recording sales from the White farm, large quantities of Beef, Pork, clover seed, cheese, milk, Cider, Ash and Chestnut Boards, 1856-1960 (Volume 2221.002)
  - George G Jacobson I b.1883- d.1959 - Journal of work done attheir saw mill and account of milk sales from their farm., 1913-1915 (Volume 2221.003)
  - Cooper Shop Account Book - James White b. 1778 d.1861 & Montgomery White b.1779- d.1865- 3 generations worked at this shop on Cooper Lane, Coventry, 1815-1824 (Volume 2026)
  - Henry Francis West b.1836- d.1903 - Diaries includes his accounts, including the sale of the Hartford Courant and charges for headstones and burial arrangements, and produce of his farm, and his expenses- 25 pocket size books., 1878-1903 (Volume 2547)
  - Bearce Machine Shop, South St Coventry-Fabrication, Machining and Welding- Nelson Bearce b. 1919- d.2017, record of work done., 1970 (Volume 2684)
  - Hat Factory Account Book - William Babcock b.1804- D.1870 -Supplies purchased, Sales, Labor-also includes Coventry death records 1835- 1861, South District School Acct., recipe for white wash and dried Salt beef., 1830-1867 (Volume 2694)
  - Hat Factory Account Book - William Babcock b.1804- d.1870 - also includes text of an address given by Edward Everett 1835, remarks by Daniel Webster on the Character of Jeremiah Mason south District School Account 1855, 1867 (Volume 2694.001)
  - Kingsbury Dairy 1956 Manchester Milk Route- Dairy owner John E. Kingsbury b.1881- d.1962, son of Andrew Kingsbury - Records Customer names and sales- includes some notes from customers (Volume 2826.021)
  - Account Book of Lewis Addison Dimock b.1809- d.1881 - later used as a scrap book, covering nany accounts, account of payment for silk skeining still visible.-N. Coventry/ Mansfield Depot farmer and businessman., 1846-1851 (Volume 2984)
  - G. Raymond Johnson b.1900- d.1977,Plumbin, Heating and Tinning- Ledger- He did extensive work in Coventry and surrounding towns., 1941-1944 (Volume 2988)
  - G. Raymond Johnson b.1900- d.1977, Plumbing, Heating and Tinning -Cash Book, 1944-1956 (Volume 2988.001)
  - G. Raymond Johnson b.1900- d.1977, Plumbing, Heating and Tinning - Alphabetical Accounts, 1944-1964 (Volume 2988.002)
  - G. Raymond Johnson b.1900- d.1977, Plumbing, Heating and Tinning -Chronilogical accounts of work done and materials used., 1949-1962 (Volume 2988.003)
  - Diary of Marcus Aspinwall b.1836- d.1909 farmer on South St. includes his farm Accounts and labor exchanged with neighbors. Typed transcription., 1903 (Volume 3055)